Data driven approaches can be very useful
データ駆動型のアプローチは
particularly when we have access to plenty of training data.
たくさんのトレーニング データにアクセスできる場合に非常に便利です
But in some ways purely data driven approaches are naïve since they rely
しかし ある意味で純粋にデータ駆動型のアプローチは
solely on historical evidence to make predictions about likely future behavior.
将来のありそうな行動について予測するために歴史的証拠に完全に頼っているため 単純ではありません
Ideally, we would also like to include, in our predictions,
理想的には 予測に
all the insights we have about driver behavior,
ドライバーの行動
physics, or vehicle dynamics.
物理と 車両力学の特性を考慮に含めるべきだと思います
This is where model based approaches can help.
これが モデル ベースのアプローチが役立つ可能性がある場所です
The way these approaches typically work is as follows.
これらのアプローチが通常どおり 機能する方法は次のとおりです
For each object identify all the behaviors
オブジェクトごとに そのオブジェクト
that object is likely to do in the current situation.
が現在の状況で実行する可能性が高い すべての動作を識別します
The behavior for a vehicle could be something like change lanes,
車両の挙動は車線変更のようなもので
turn left and for a pedestrian,
左折し 歩行者の場合は
it could be cross the street on pedestrian crossing.
横断歩道を渡ることができるようなものです
For our intersection scenario,
交差点のシナリオでは
the behaviors could be go straight,
動作は
turn left, turn right.
直進 左折 または右折です
Whatever it is, it needs to be something that we can describe mathematically.
何であれ 数学的に説明できるものである必要があります
Step two, define a process model for each behavior.
ステップ 2 では 各動作のプロセスモデルを定義します
A process model is a mathematical description of object motion for behavior.
プロセス モデルは 行動のためのオブジェクトの動作の数学的記述です
It is a function which can be used to compute the state of
この関数は
time t. The process model must
時刻 t の状態から t_plus_1 のオブジェクトを計算するために使用できます  このプロセス モデル
incorporate some uncertainty which represents how much we trust our model.
は モデルをどれだけ信頼しているかを表す不確実性を取り入れます
In our intersection example,
交差点の例では
the left turn process model would produce an uncertain future state located roughly here.
左折のプロセス モデルは おおよその場所に位置する不確実な将来の状態を生み出します
The going straight process model would produce an uncertain future state located roughly
直進のプロセス モデルは おおよそ
here and the right turn process model would
の場所に位置する不確実な将来の状態を生み出します 右折のプロセスモデルは
produce an uncertain future state located roughly here.
ここにある不確実な将来の状態を作り出します
If you keep running the process models your uncertainty will increase.
プロセス モデルを実行し続けると 不確実性が増します
Once we have a process model for each behavior we can go to the next step,
各動作のプロセス モデルが完成したら 次のステップ
step three, which is to use
であるステップ 3 に進むことができます
the process models to compute the probability of each behavior.
ここで プロセス モデルを使用して各動作の確率を計算します
This is done by taking the observed state of the object at time t_minus_1,
これは 時刻 t_minus_1 におけるオブジェクトの観測状態を取得することによって行われます
running the process models to compute the expected state of the object at time t.
ここで プロセス モデルを実行して 時刻 t におけるオブジェクトの予想状態を計算します
Then we compare the observed state of the object at
それから
time t with what our process models predicted.
時刻 T におけるオブジェクトの観測状態を プロセス モデルの予測と比較します
And we use a multimodal estimation algorithm to derive the probability of each maneuver.
各操作の確率を導出するためにマルチモーダル推定アルゴリズムを使用します
The purpose of these algorithms is to maintain some belief about
これらのアルゴリズムの目的は
how likely it is that the driver intends to perform each behavior.
ドライバーがそれぞれの動作を実行しようとする頻度について 信頼性を維持することです
We'll go into more detail later.
後ほど これについて詳細に説明します
But in this case the probability of going straight
この場合 直進する可能性
or turning left would be higher than the probability of turning right.
左折する確率は 右折する確率よりも高くなります
The fourth and final step is to predict a trajectory for each behavior.
最後の 4 番目のステップは 各行動のトラジェクトリーを予測することです
This is done easily by iterating on
これは 予測範囲に達するまでプロセス モデルを
the process models until the prediction horizon is reached.
繰り返すことで簡単に行えます
In the following videos,
次のビデオでは
we talk more about the process models we use to model behaviors and then
行動をモデル化するために使用するプロセス モデルについて説明します
discuss one version of
その後 概念を維持するために使用できる
multimodal estimation algorithm that can be used to maintain beliefs.
マルチモーダル推定アルゴリズムの 1 つのバージョンを破棄します